caregiverstress.com 2019-12-17

# Home Instead Senior Care - Privacy Policy

For the Canadian Privacy Policy, click here.

##  **U.S. Privacy Policy**  
​(updated February 25, 2019)

We at Home Instead, Inc. ("Home Instead" or "we" or "us" or "our") appreciate your interest in this website and other websites operated by us on which this Privacy Policy is linked (this website and each other Home Instead website on which this Privacy Policy is linked are each and collectively hereinafter in this Privacy Policy referred to as the "Site").

Your privacy is important and we are committed to protecting the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that you disclose to us. We want you to understand our practices with respect to how we gather and use the information we collect from visitors to the Site. This Privacy Policy covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our Site and our Social Media Properties (as more fully described below) and how that information may be used or shared by us, our affiliates, independently owned and operated franchises/master franchises, and third parties.

Home Instead Senior Care franchise and master franchise businesses are independently owned and operated.  This privacy policy does not apply to any sites independently operated by such franchise businesses or to such franchisee’s use of the franchisee’s own data for purposes, including communication, provision of services, administration, or payment.  If you are receiving communications from a Home Instead Senior Care franchise, you must contact that franchise directly in order to opt out from their communications.

**This Privacy Policy is subject to change.** If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on the Site prior to the change becoming effective. **We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically and to make note of the date of the most recent revision. If you disagree with the manner in which we intend to use the Personal Information you provide to us, you may opt out of these uses by following the instructions below. By using our Site, you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy in effect at that time and as may be updated from time to time.**

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us at 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154, [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com), or 1.888.484.5759.

## Information We Collect

We collect both Personal Information and non-personally identifiable information through the Site in order to help us to learn more about how our visitors use the Site, to measure areas of interest, and to provide our users with important information on our network of independently owned and operated Home Instead Senior Care® franchise businesses (the "Network") and our and/or our Network's services. Collection of information allows us to build features and functionality that will enhance your experience. You are not obligated to provide us with Personal Information in order to use the Site. However, we do require that you register and provide certain Personal Information in order to send us inquiries, to receive information about our Network and how to become an independently owned and individually operated franchise (each a "Franchise") or master franchise (each a "Master Franchise"), and to receive newsletters and other special offers. We collect non-personally identifiable information through the use of General Tracking Information and Click Path Tracking (cookie technology) described below.

## Collection of Non-Personally Identifiable Information

### 1\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Personal Information is information that is about an identifiable individual. Generally speaking, Personal Information does not include: a) anonymous or aggregated information that does not allow an individual to be identified; or b) information regarding companies and other "legal persons."

### 2\. General Tracking Information

We keep track of the pages visited by each user. Our web server automatically collects some information about you when you request pages from our server, including your IP address. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you. We aggregate this data with data on the pages visited by other users to track overall visitor traffic patterns. We use this information to improve our Site by making it more responsive to the needs and preferences of our users. This information does not identify you personally.

### 3\. Click Path Tracking

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Home Instead and our affiliates, our marketing, testing and quality assurance partners, and/or our analytics, information technology and web monitoring service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Site, tracking users' movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. Mobile applications may also use cookies. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to help improve the services we and/or our Network offer you and to help improve marketing, analytics, or Site functionality.

We use local storage ("LS") also referred to as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use local storage to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS.

At any given time, we may partner with one or more third party advertisers, search providers and/or ad networks to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Each such third party advertiser, search provider and ad network partner may use cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on the Site and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by contacting us at 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154, [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com), or 1.888.484.5759. Please note that this does not opt you out of being served generic, non-targeted advertising. You will continue to receive generic, non-targeted ads.

### 4\. Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

We may share non-personally identifiable information in the aggregated form with third parties who are providing research services that, in turn, will help to enhance the experiences of the Network's clients or CAREGiversSM. These third parties may publish the results of these research findings (e.g., in academic environments).

## Collection of Personal Information

If you choose to register on our Site, you will be asked to provide Personal Information which may include your name, mailing address, e-mail address, and phone number. Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we do not actively share Personal Information gathered from our web servers. When you register, we will place your name in our mailing list and will send you an e-mail to the address you have provided to confirm your registration on our Site.

### 1\. What we do with the Personal Information We Collect

We collect Personal Information from you in order to learn more about how you use the Site; to measure areas of interest in our Network and the services we and/or the Network provide(s); to understand the needs of our and our Network's customers; to provide you with better service; and to help us with internal record keeping. If you register or use the "chat" feature on our Site, the information you provide through your registration, or as part of the chat feature, may be used by Home Instead, our independently owned and operated Franchisees and Master Franchisees, our affiliates and our third-party service providers or other partners for gathering business intelligence about our Network or performing data analytics and may be compiled as part of our internal database system. In addition, both we and our independently owned and operated Franchisees and Master Franchisees, affiliates, third-party service providers and other business partners may send correspondence to or contact you using the e-mail, street address and/or phone number you provide to us when registering on our Site or which you provide to us through the Site. These communications may include, but are not limited to, newsletters, promotional offers, information on new features and services that we and/or our Network provide(s), franchise opportunities, employment opportunities with us at our corporate office, Site updates, responses to your e-mails, inquiries, comments and opinions, surveys, and technical support. In certain instances you will have an opportunity to limit these uses at the time your Personal Information is collected. You also may limit the contacts you receive by following the instructions in the "Opt-Out" Section below.

We and/or our Network will retain and use your information for as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce agreements.

### 2\. Sharing of Personal Information

We will share your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We currently do not provide or sell any Personal Information to marketing research or bulk advertising sales companies or to any other third parties. We will share your Personal Information with our independently owned and operated Franchisees and Master Franchisees and affiliates who are bound to protect such information from disclosure or misuse. We, or our affiliates, may use your Personal Information to follow up on your interest in receiving our Network's services and/or if you express interest in potential employment with our Home Office. Our Franchisees, Master Franchisees and affiliates may use your Personal Information to follow-up on your interest in receiving Network services and/or if you express interest in potential employment by our Franchisees or Master Franchisees. We may share your Personal Information with third-party businesses who offer services that we determine may be helpful to people who are or may be interested in the Network's services or resources. As described above, you may limit this sharing by following the instructions in the "Opt-Out" Section below. We may also disclose Personal Information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this Personal Information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may have breached our Terms of Use or who may be causing (whether intentionally or unintentionally) injury to or interference with our rights or property, other website users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information to law-enforcement personnel and agencies when requested to do so, as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or if Home Instead is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets.

We may also provide your Personal Information to or allow access to your Personal Information by companies that provide services to help us or the Network with our/its business activities, such as offering customer service, assessing quality and customer satisfaction, enabling website features, or assisting with hiring of employees. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services.

### 3\. Click-to-Chat Conversations

Any personal information that you share during any click-to-chat conversation will be considered Personal Information that may be used and retained in accordance with this Privacy Policy. As a click-to-chat conversation may not be a secure form of communication, please do not provide any social security numbers, credit card numbers, or other sensitive information during any click-to-chat conversation in which you elect to participate.

### 4\. Hilarity for Charity® Respite Care Grant Applications

If you apply for a Hilarity for Charity® respite care grant via our Help for Alzheimer's Families Site, any personal information that is include in the application that your submit via the Site will be considered Personal Information that may be used and retained in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, we will share this Personal Information with the Hilarity for Charity® review board for its consideration of your application and, if you are awarded a respite care grant, the Franchisee that may provide such respite care. We will also store this Personal Information for purposes of responding to any inquiries you may have about your application after it is submitted.

## Links to Third Party Websites

Occasionally our Site may include a hyperlink ("Link") or a banner advertisement ("Banner Ad") containing a Link which allows you to connect to the home page of a third party website ("Third Party Site"), the independent website of a Franchisee ("Franchisee Site") or the website of a Master Franchisee ("Master Franchisee Site")(such as a US Franchisee website not using "homeinstead.com"). Home Instead or the Network may provide these Links to you as a convenient method of accessing information that may be useful or of interest to you. This Privacy Policy and the practices that we follow under this Privacy Policy do not apply to Third Party Sites, Franchisee Sites or Master Franchisee Sites that are operated independently from Home Instead.

We are not responsible for the content, accuracy, or opinions expressed on any Franchisee Site, Master Franchisee Site or Third Party Site or for the privacy practices of our Franchisees and Master Franchisees or any third party. We will not, and are under no obligation to, investigate, monitor or check the Franchisee Sites, Master Franchisee Sites or Third Party Sites for accuracy or completeness, or for any obscene, scandalous, inflammatory, pornographic, indecent, profane, defamatory or unlawful content or materials. Inclusion of any Link or Banner Ad to a Third Party Site, or Franchisee Site or Master Franchisee Site that is placed on our Site does not imply approval or endorsement of the Third Party Site, Franchisee Site or Master Franchisee Site. You understand and agree that by clicking on a Link to a Third Party Site, Franchisee Site, or Master Franchisee Site you have left the Site, and the Home Instead Privacy Policy stated on the Site is no longer in effect.

## Social Media

**Any information, including personal information, that you choose to share in any online message board, forum, or via social medial is by design open to the public and not private.**   You should think carefully before posting any personal information via social media.  What you post can be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we cannot control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes.  As with any social media or public forum, the information you post may show up in third-party search engines.

### 1\. Social Media Sharing

Our Site includes social media sharing tools and features, such as Facebook Like, YouTube, Twitter and “share” buttons and widgets, and interactive mini-programs that run on our Site (each a “Feature” and, collectively, the “Features”). These Features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Site, and set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site.

### 2\. Social Media Message Boards and Public Forums 

Social medial message boards and public forums provide users with similar interests and concerns a place to share information and support one another, post questions, or enter into moderated online discussions.  We maintain profiles or accounts with various third-party social media providers, including, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Google+ and may also provide our own message boards and forums utilizing the services of a third-party, including the Your Caregiver Guide public forum.  (each individually and collectively referred to as “Social Media Properties.”)

Your interactions with these Social Media Properties and/or the Features are governed by multiple privacy policies. While our collection, use, and disclosure of information obtained through the Social Media Properties and/or the Features is governed by this Privacy Policy to the same extent as information gathered through the Site, the information third-party social media providers collect or access through your use of the Social Media Properties is governed by such third-party’s privacy policy.  We encourage you to review the social media provider’s privacy policy before interacting with a Social Media Property and/or Feature.

## Security

To reduce the possibility of unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place a number of physical, electronic and managerial procedures to help protect the information we collect online. In addition, we use standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificates to secure all pages used for inputting users' Personal Information. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, no system can be completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information.

## California Do Not Track Disclosure

Do Not Track is a web browser privacy preference that causes the web browser to broadcast a signal to websites requesting the user's activity that such activity will not be tracked. Home Instead's Site does not respond to Do Not Track signals.

## Opt-Out

You may choose to have your name taken off of our registration list, cease receiving correspondence or newsletters from us, limit our sharing of Personal Information with third parties who may offer services to you, or update or delete the Personal Information that you have provided to us via one of the following methods:

  * Using the opt-out option in any e-mails or text messages you receive from us;
  * Sending us an e-mail at: [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com);
  * Writing to us at: Home Instead, Inc., 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154; or
  * Calling us toll free at: 1.888.484.5759

We will respond to your request within 10 days.

Opting out of one form of communication does not mean you have opted out of other forms as well. For example, if you opt out of receiving marketing emails, you may still receive marketing text messages if you have opted in to receiving them.  If you submit a general opt out request, we will unsubscribe you based upon the information provided.  For example, if you provide your name, email address, and phone number we will unsubscribe you from any lists linked to either your name, email address or phone number.  If you wish to opt out of communications from a Home Instead Senior Care franchise, you must contact that franchise directly.   

## International Visitors

This Site is hosted in the United States and is intended only for United States and Canadian visitors. This website is not intended for users located within the European Economic Area. We may share, as described in this Privacy Policy, your personal information with our affiliates, subsidiaries, independently owned and operated Home Instead Senior Care franchise and master franchise businesses, and third parties. Please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province or country and that such information is processed and stored in the United States. By providing your personal information, you confirm your consent to having such personal data hosted and accessed in the United States.

## Disclaimer

The data contained in our Site is for informational purposes only and is not represented to be error free. Home Instead attempts to ensure that the data provided or otherwise displayed on our Site is accurate. However, the Site and its contents are provided on an "as is, as available" basis. Use of the Site and its contents is at your sole risk. Home Instead does not warrant that any functions of the Site will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that the Site will be free from viruses or other harmful components. Home Instead makes no warranties, either express or implied, concerning the content of the Site, including the accuracy, completeness, reliability or suitability of the Site.

## Guidelines for Children

We do not specifically collect information about children nor market our and our Network's products or services to children. We have no reason to believe that the Site will attract children, or that children will access the Site or provide Personal Information.

## Blogs

The Site may offer publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog, contact us at [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Testimonials

The Site may display personal testimonials in addition to other endorsements.

Our Site may enable you to post public comments, feedback, or reviews, through a Third Party Site. While the collection, use and disclosure of information you post on this Site is governed by this Privacy, personal testimonials posted publicly on a Third Party Site are also governed by that site's privacy policy. We encourage you to review the applicable site's privacy policy before publishing such public comments, feedback or reviews. By publishing a personal testimonial through a Third Party Site, you consent that we may post your testimonial along with your name.

Network customers may also submit a personal testimonial through other channels where consent to posting the customer's name and testimonial is requested and provided prior to use.

If you wish to update or delete your testimonial on our Site, you can contact us at [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com).

## Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service to email a friend about the Site, we will ask you for your name, email address and your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site and may use your friend's email address in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Your friend may contact us at [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Termination of Use

You agree that we may, in our sole discretion, terminate or suspend your access to all or any part of the Site with or without notice and for any reason. Any suspected fraudulent, abusive or illegal activity may be grounds for terminating your access to and use of the Site, and if we believe that you have committed such acts, we may report you to appropriate law enforcement authorities.

## Choice

We collect information for our independently owned and operated Franchisees and Master Franchisees. If you are a customer or employee of one of our Franchisees or Master Franchisees and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Franchisees or Master Franchisees that use our service, please contact the Franchisee or Master Franchisee that you interact with directly.

## Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer

Home Instead may transfer Personal Information to companies that help us and our Network provide our and the Network's respective services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Privacy Policy regarding notice and choice, the franchise agreements with our Franchisees and the master franchise agreements with our Master Franchisees.

## Franchisees & Master Franchisees

If you are accessing the Site as an independently owned and operated Franchisee or Master Franchisee, or as an employee or contractor of such Franchisee or Master Franchisee, your access and use of the Site is also governed by the franchise agreement or master franchise agreement applicable to your business, as applicable, which is incorporated herein by reference.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Site, or your dealings with the Site, please contact:

**Home Instead, Inc.**  
 **13323 California Street**  
 **Omaha, NE 68154**   

1.888.484.5759

If you have any questions regarding a Home Instead Senior Care franchisee business’ privacy practices or wish to opt-out of its communications, please contact the franchise office directly.

 _Each Home Instead Senior Care franchise office is independently owned and operated._  

​​​​​ 

## ​ **Canadian Privacy Policy**   
(updated February 25, 2019)

We at Home Instead, Inc. ("Home Instead" or "we" or "us" or "our") appreciate your interest in this website and other websites operated by us and to which this Privacy Policy is linked (this website and each other Home Instead website on which this Privacy Policy is linked are each and collectively hereinafter in this Privacy Policy referred to as the "Site").

Your privacy is important and we are committed to protecting the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that you disclose to us. We want you to understand our practices with respect to how we gather and use the information we collect from visitors to the Site. This Privacy Policy covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our Site and our Social Media Properties (as more fully described below) and how that information may be used or shared by us, our affiliates independently owned and operated franchises/ master franchises, and third parties.

Home Instead Senior Care franchise and master franchise businesses are independently owned and operated.  This privacy policy does not apply to any sites independently operated by such franchise businesses or to such franchisee’s use of the franchisee’s own data for purposes, including communication, provision of services, administration, or payment.  If you are receiving communications from a Home Instead Senior Care franchise, you must contact that franchise directly in order to opt out from their communications.   

**This Privacy Policy is subject to change.** If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on the Site prior to the change becoming effective. **We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically and to make note of the date of the most recent revision. If you disagree with the manner in which we intend to use the Personal Information you provide to us, you may opt out of these uses by following the instructions below. By using our Site, you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy in effect at that time and as may be updated from time to time.**

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us at 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154, [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com), or 1.888.484.5759.

## Information We Collect

We collect both Personal Information and non-personally identifiable information through the Site in order to help us to learn more about how our visitors use the Site, to measure areas of interest, and to provide our users with important information on our network of independently owned and operated Home Instead Senior Care® franchise businesses (the "Network") and our and/or our Network's services. Collection of information allows us to build features and functionality that will enhance your experience. You are not obligated to provide us with Personal Information in order to use the Site. However, we do require that you register and provide certain Personal Information in order to send us inquiries, to receive information about our Network and how to become an independently owned and individually operated franchise (each a "Franchise") or master franchise (each a "Master Franchise"), and to receive newsletters and other special offers. We collect non-personally identifiable information through the use of General Tracking Information and Click Path Tracking (cookie technology) described below.

## Collection of Non-Personally Identifiable Information

### 1\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Personal Information is information that is about an identifiable individual. Generally speaking, Personal Information does not include: a) anonymous or aggregated information that does not allow an individual to be identified; or b) information regarding companies and other "legal persons." Business contact information such as your name, title or position, business address, telephone number or fax number is Personal Information but under applicable privacy laws, however, your consent is not required to use this information to contact you in your employment, business or professional capacity. All information that is not Personal Information is Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

### 2\. General Tracking Information

We keep track of the pages visited by each user. Our web server automatically collects some information about you when you request pages from our server, including your IP address. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you. We aggregate this data with data on the pages visited by other users to track overall visitor traffic patterns. We use this information to improve our Site by making it more responsive to the needs and preferences of our users. This information does not identify you personally.

### 3\. Click Path Tracking

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Home Instead and our affiliates, our marketing, testing and quality assurance partners, and/or our analytics, information technology and web monitoring service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Site, tracking users' movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. Mobile applications may also use cookies. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to help improve the services we and/or our Network offer you and to help improve marketing, analytics, or Site functionality.

We use local storage ("LS") also referred to as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use local storage to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS.

At any given time, we may partner with one or more third party advertisers, search providers and/or ad networks to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Each such third party advertiser, search provider and ad network partner may use cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on the Site and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by contacting us at 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154, [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com), or 1.888.484.5759. Please note that this does not opt you out of being served generic, non-targeted advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### 4\. Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We may share non-personally identifiable information in the aggregated form with third parties who are providing research services that, in turn, will help to enhance the experiences of the Network's clients or CAREGiversSM. These third parties may publish the results of these research findings (e.g., in academic environments).

## Collection of Personal Information

If you choose to register on our Site, you will be asked to provide Personal Information which may include your name, mailing address, e-mail address, and phone number. Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we do not share Personal Information gathered from our web servers. When you register, we will place your name in our mailing list and will send you an e-mail to the address you have provided to confirm your registration on our Site.

### 1\. What we do with the Personal Information We Collect

We collect Personal Information from you in order to learn more about how you use the Site; to measure areas of interest in our Network and the services we and/or the Network provide(s); to understand the needs of our and our Network's customers; and to provide you with better service. If you register or use the "chat" feature on our Site, the information you provide through registration or as part of the chat feature may be used by Home Instead, our Franchisees and Master Franchisees, our affiliates and our third-party service providers or other partners for gathering business intelligence about our Network or performing data analytics and may be compiled as part of our internal database system. In addition, we (including our Franchisees, Master Franchisees, affiliates, third-party service providers and other business partners) may send correspondence to or contact you using the e-mail, street address and/or phone number you provide to us when registering on our Site or using the chat feature on our Site. We may contact you to provide newsletters, promotional offers, information on new features and services that we and/or our Network provide(s), franchise opportunities, employment opportunities with us at our corporate office, Site updates, responses to your e-mails, inquiries, comments and opinions, surveys, and technical support. For any electronic marketing messages that we may send to you, we will, at the time of collecting your electronic address, seek your express, opt-in consent to send you these messages. You will always have the right to opt out of receiving electronic marketing messages from us. Please see our Opt-Out section below.

We and/or our Network will retain and use your information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, or as permitted or required by law. 

### 2\. Sharing of Personal Information

We will share your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We currently do not provide or sell any Personal Information to marketing research or bulk advertising sales companies or to any other third parties. We will share your Personal Information with our Franchisees, Master Franchisees and affiliates who are bound to protect such information from disclosure or misuse. Our Franchisees, Master Franchisees and affiliates may use your Personal Information to follow-up on your interest in receiving Network services and/or if you express interest in potential employment by our Franchisees or Master Franchisees. We may also provide your information to our affiliates who may use your Personal Information to follow-up if you express interest in potential employment with our Home Office. We may also share your Personal Information with third-party businesses who offer services that may be helpful to people who are or may be interested in the Network's services or resources. As described above, you may limit this sharing by following the instructions in the "Opt-Out" Section below. We may also disclose Personal Information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this Personal Information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may have breached our Terms of Use or who may be causing (whether intentionally or unintentionally) injury to or interference with our rights or property, other website users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information to law-enforcement personnel and agencies when requested to do so, as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or if Home Instead is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets.

We may also provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us or the Network with our/its business activities, such as offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services. Some of these service providers are located outside of Canada and your Personal Information may be stored and/or processed outside of Canada. If you would like more information about our policies concerning our use of service providers outside of Canada, please contact our Privacy Officer at the address listed under "Contact Information" below.

### 3\. Maintenance of Personal Information

We will update Personal Information as and when necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected or upon notification from you. Home Instead will not routinely update Personal Information, unless such process is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected. If ever your contact and/or other Personal Information changes, please feel free to contact us so that we can update our records.

### 4\. Hilarity for Charity® Respite Care Grant Applications

If you apply for a Hilarity for Charity respite care grant via our Help for Alzheimer's Families Site, any personal information that is included in the application that you submit via the Site will be considered Personal Information that may be used and retained in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, we will share this Personal Information with the Hilarity for Charity review board for its consideration of your application and, if you are awarded a respite care grant, the Franchisee that may provide such respite care. We will also store this Personal Information for purposes of responding to any inquiries you may have about your application after it is submitted.

## Openness

We ensure information about our Privacy Policy and our practices relating to the management of Personal Information is available to you. For example, we will provide you, upon request with (a) the name or title, and the address, of the Privacy Officer to whom complaints or inquiries can be forwarded; (b) how to gain access to your Personal Information in our possession or control; (c) a description of the type of Personal Information we hold about you, including a general account of its use and (d) what Personal Information is made available to related organizations, i.e.: affiliated companies.

We may make information on our Privacy Policy and practices available in a variety of ways. The method chosen depends on a number of considerations. For example, we may choose to make brochures available in our place of business, mail information to our users or provide online access.

Upon request, subject to certain exceptions under applicable privacy legislation, you we will inform of the existence, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information and will give you access to that information. You may wish to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the Personal Information and have it amended as appropriate.

NOTE: In certain situations, under privacy laws, we may not be able to provide access to all of your Personal Information we hold. The reasons for denying access will be provided to you upon request. Exceptions may include information that contains references to other individuals, information that cannot be disclosed for legal, security, or commercial proprietary reasons, and information that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege. We may charge a reasonable administration fee for accessing Personal Information.

## Links to Third Party Websites

Occasionally we may include on our Site a hyperlink ("Link") or a banner advertisement ("Banner Ad") containing a Link which allows you to connect to the home page of a third party website ("Third Party Site"), the website of a Franchisee ("Franchisee Site") or the website of a Master Franchisee ("Master Franchisee Site")(such as a Canadian Franchisee website not using "homeinstead.com"). Home Instead or the Network may provide these Links to you as a convenient method of accessing information that may be useful or of interest to you. This Privacy Policy and the practices that we follow under this Privacy Policy do not apply to Third Party Sites, Franchisee Sites or Master Franchisee Sites that are operated independently from Home Instead.

We are not responsible for the content, accuracy, or opinions expressed on any Franchisee Site, Master Franchisee Site or Third Party Site or for the privacy practices of our Franchisees, Master Franchisees or any third party. We will not, and are under no obligation to, investigate, monitor or check the Franchisee Sites, Master Franchisee Sites or Third Party Sites for accuracy or completeness, or for any obscene, scandalous, inflammatory, pornographic, indecent, profane, defamatory or unlawful content or materials. Inclusion of any Link or Banner Ad to a Third Party Site, or Franchisee Site or Master Franchisee Site that is placed on our Site does not imply approval or endorsement of the Third Party Site, Franchisee Site or Master Franchisee Site. You understand and agree that by clicking on a Link to a Third Party Site, Franchisee Site, or Master Franchisee Site you have left the Site, and the Home Instead Privacy Policy stated on the Site is no longer in effect.

## Social Media

Our Site includes social media sharing tools and features, such as Facebook Like, YouTube, Twitter and "share" buttons and widgets, and interactive mini-programs that run on our Site (each a "Feature" and, collectively, the "Features"). These Features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Site, and set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site.

We also maintain profiles or accounts with various social media providers, including, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Google+ (collectively, "Social Media Properties"). Your interactions with these Social Media Properties and/or the Features are governed by multiple privacy policies. Our collection, use and disclosure of information obtained through the Social Media Properties and/or the Features is governed by this Privacy Policy to the same extent as information gathered through the Site; however, the privacy practices of the applicable social media provider are governed by the applicable social media provider's privacy policy. We encourage you to review the applicable social media provider's privacy policy before interacting with a Social Media Property and/or Feature.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your Personal Information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Our hardware, software, and security infrastructure as well as our internal standards for the Site meet current industry standards and technology. In addition, we use standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificates to secure all pages used for inputting users' Personal Information. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between us will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.

## Accountability

Home Instead has designated an individual as the person who is accountable for our compliance with our commitments in this Privacy Policy (our "Privacy Officer"). As such, accountability for our compliance with the Privacy Policy rests with the Privacy Officer, even though other individuals within our organization may be responsible for the day-to-day collection and processing of Personal Information. In addition, other individuals within Home Instead may be delegated to act on behalf of the Privacy Officer. We will make the identity of our Privacy Officer known to you upon request. We remain responsible for Personal Information that is in our possession or control, including information that has been transferred to a third party for processing. In such circumstances, we use contractual or other means to provide a comparable level of protection while the information is being processed by the third party.

## Opt-Out

You may choose to have your name taken off of our registration list, cease receiving correspondence or newsletters from us, limit our sharing of Personal Information with third parties who may offer services to you, or update or delete the Personal Information that you have provided to us via one of the following methods:

  * Using the opt-out option in any e-mails or text messages you receive from us;
  * Sending us an e-mail at: [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com);
  * Writing to us at: Home Instead, Inc., 13323 California Street, Omaha, NE 68154; or
  * Calling us toll free at: 1.888.484.5759

We will respond to your request within 10 days.

Opting out of one form of communication does not mean you have opted out of other forms as well. For example, if you opt out of receiving marketing emails, you may still receive marketing text messages if you have opted in to receiving them.  If you submit a general opt out request, we will unsubscribe you based upon the information provided.  For example, if you provide your name, email address, and phone number we will unsubscribe you from any lists linked to either your name, email address or phone number.  If you wish to opt out of communications from a Home Instead Senior Care franchise, you must contact that franchise directly.   

## International Visitors

This Site is hosted in the United States and is intended only for United States and Canadian visitors. This website is not intended for users located within the European Economic Area. We may share, as described in this Privacy Policy, your personal information with our affiliates, subsidiaries, independently owned and operated Home Instead Senior Care franchise and master franchise businesses, and third parties. Please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province or country and that such information is processed and stored in the United States. By providing your personal information, you confirm your consent to having such personal data hosted and accessed in the United States.

## Disclaimer

The data contained in our Site is for informational purposes only and is not represented to be error free. Home Instead attempts to ensure that the data provided or otherwise displayed on our Site is accurate. However, the Site and its contents are provided on an "as is, as available" basis. Use of the Site and its contents is at your sole risk. Home Instead does not warrant that any functions of the Site will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that the Site will be free from viruses or other harmful components. Home Instead makes no warranties, either express or implied, concerning the content of the Site, including the accuracy, completeness, reliability or suitability of the Site.

## Guidelines for Children

We do not specifically collect information about children nor market our and our Network's products or services to children. We have no reason to believe that the Site will attract children, or that children will access the Site or provide Personal Information.

## Blogs

The Site may offer publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog, contact us at [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers of ours or our Network on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com](mailto:dataprivacy@homeinsteadinc.com).

Our Site may enable you to post public comments, feedback, or reviews, through a Third Party Site. While the collection, use and disclosure of information you post on this Site is governed by this Privacy, personal testimonials posted publicly on a Third Party Site are also governed by that site's privacy policy. We encourage you to review the applicable site's privacy policy before publishing such public comments, feedback or reviews. By publishing a personal testimonial through a Third Party Site, you consent that we may post your testimonial along with your name.

## Termination of Use

You agree that we may, in our sole discretion, terminate or suspend your access to all or any part of the Site with or without notice and for any reason. Any suspected fraudulent, abusive or illegal activity may be grounds for terminating our relationship, and if we believe that you have committed such acts, we may report you to appropriate law enforcement authorities.

## Choice

We collect information for our Franchisees and Master Franchisees. If you are a customer or employee of one of our Franchisees or Master Franchisees and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Franchisees or Master Franchisees that use our service, please contact the Franchisee or Master Franchisee that you interact with directly.

## Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer

Home Instead may transfer Personal Information to service providers that help us and our Network provide our and the Network's respective services to you.

## Franchisees & Master Franchisees

If you are accessing the Site as an independently owned and operated Franchisee or Master Franchisee, or as an employee or contractor of such Franchisee or Master Franchisee, your access and use of the Site is also governed by the franchise agreement or master franchise agreement applicable to your business, as applicable, which is incorporated herein by reference.

## Contact Information

If ​​​​​you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Site, or your dealings with the Site, please contact:

**Home Instead, Inc.**  
 **13323 California Street**  
 **Omaha, NE 68154**   
1.888.484.5759

If you have any questions regarding a Home Instead Senior Care franchisee business’ privacy practices or wish to opt-out of its communications, please contact the franchise office directly.
